<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Basics Of Islam</string>
    <string name="Inters" translatable="false">ca-app-pub-2868811788162661/6313921516</string>
    <string name="APP_ID" translatable="false">ca-app-pub-2868811788162661~6505493207</string>
    <string name="alert" translatable="false">Basic language of this app is english and all
        other translation are done with automated tools which may have some contextual mistakes.
        Please refer to english if there are some confusions</string>

    <string name="WhenWakingUp">When Waking Up</string>
    <string name="wearinggarment">When wearing new Garment</string>
    <string name="someonewearnewgar">Said to someone wearing new Garment </string>
    <string name="beforeundress">Before Undressing</string>
    <string name="beforetoilet">Before Entering Toilet</string>
    <string name="leavingtoilet">After Leaving Toilet</string>
    <string name="startablution">When Starting ablution</string>
    <string name="completeablution">Upon Completing ablution</string>
    <string name="leavinghome">When Leaving Home</string>
    <string name="enteringhome">Upon Entering Home</string>
    <string name="goingtomosque">When Going To Mosque</string>
    <string name="enteringmosque">Upon Entering Mosque</string>
    <string name="leavemosque">Leaving Mosque</string>
    <string name="azan">Related To Azan</string>
    <string name="aftertakbeer">Start of Prayer (After Takbeer)</string>
    <string name="rukooa">During Rukooaa (Bowing)</string>
    <string name="risingrukoo">Upon Rising from Rukooa</string>
    <string name="duringsujood">During Sujood (Prostrating)</string>
    <string name="betweensujood">Between Two Sujood</string>
    <string name="afterrecquran">Sujood After reciting Quran</string>
    <string name="tashahhud">The Tashahhud</string>
    <string name="aftertashahhud">Prayers after Tashahhud</string>
    <string name="beforesalam">After last Tashahhud and before salam</string>
    <string name="aftersalam">Remembrance After Salam</string>
    <string name="istikhara">Dua For Istikhara</string>
    <string name="inmornandeve">In Moring and Evening</string>
    <string name="beforesleeping">Before Sleeping</string>
    <string name="duringturningnight">During Turning over in night</string>
    <string name="feelingunrestsleep">Upon feeling unrest and fear during sleep</string>
    <string name="upondream">Upon seeing a dream</string>
    <string name="qunootalwitr">Qunoot-Al-Witr</string>
    <string name="aftersalamofwitr">After salam of witr</string>
    <string name="foranxiety">For Anxiety and Sorrow</string>
    <string name="oneindistress">For one in Distress</string>
    <string name="encounteringenemy">Upon encountering and enemy</string>
    <string name="doubtinfaith">For on having doubt in faith</string>
    <string name="settleadebt">When settling a debt</string>
    <string name="whisperinginprayer">When affected by whispering during prayer or Recitation</string>
    <string name="affairsdifficult">Dua when affairs become difficult</string>
    <string name="sin">Upon Committing a sin</string>
    <string name="expelldevil">For expelling devil and his whispering</string>
    <string name="mishap">Supplication when stricken with a mishap or overtaken by an affair</string>
    <string name="childrenprotec">Placing children under Allah\'s protection</string>
    <string name="visitingsic">When visiting sick</string>
    <string name="sickexcel">Excellence of visiting sick</string>
    <string name="losthopeforlife">Dua for sick who lost hope for life</string>
    <string name="instforoneneardeath">Instructions for one near death</string>
    <string name="affectedcalamity">When affected by calamity</string>
    <string name="closingeyesofdeceased">When closing eyes of deceased</string>
    <string name="atfuneral">At funeral</string>
    <string name="market">When entering market</string>
    <string name="wakedua1" translatable="false">اَلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ الَّذي أَحْيَانَا بَعْدَ مَا أَمَاتَنَا وَإِلَيْهِ النُّشُورُ</string>
    <string name="tr1">All praise is for Allah who gave us life after having taken it from
        us and unto Him is the resurrection.</string>
    <string name="tc2" translatable="false">لا إلهَ إلاّ اللّه وحدَهُ لا شريكَ لهُ، لهُ المُلْـكُ ولهُ الحَمْـد،
        يُحْيـي وَيُميـتُ وَهُوَ حَيٌّ لا يَمـوت،
        بِيَـدِهِ الْخَـيْرُ وَهوَ على كلّ شيءٍ قدير</string>
    <string name="trcase2">None has the right to be worshipped except Allah,
        alone, without partner, to Him belongs all sovereignty and praise.
        He gives life and causes death, and He is living and does not die.
        In His hand is all good and He is over all things, omnipotent.</string>
    <string name="dc1" translatable="false">اَلْحَمْدُ لِلّٰہِ الَّذِیْ کَسَانِیْ ھٰذَا وَرَزَقَنِیْہِ مِنْ غَیْرِ حَوْلٍ مِّنِّیْ وَلَاقُوَّةٍ۔</string>
    <string name="tc1">All Praise is for Allah who has clothed me with this garment and provided it for me,
        with no power nor might from myself.</string>
    <string name="dc3" translatable="false">تُبْلِي وَيُخْلِفُ اللَّهُ</string>
    <string name="tc3">May Allah prolong your life so that this clothing become old
        and may Allah give you other clothing after this.</string>
    <string name="dc4" translatable="false">بِسْمِ الله</string>
    <string name="tc4">In the name of Allah.</string>
    <string name="dc5" translatable="false">(بِسْمِ الله ) اللّهُـمَّ إِنِّـي أَعـوذُ بِـكَ مِـنَ الْخُـبْثِ وَالْخَبائِث</string>
    <string name="tc5">(In the name of Allah). O Allah, I take refuge with you from all evil and evil-doers.</string>
    <string name="dc6" translatable="false">غُفْـرانَك</string>
    <string name="tc6">I ask You (Allah) for forgiveness.</string>
    <string name="tc7" translatable="false">بِسْمِ الله</string>
    <string name="tc7ac">In the name of Allah</string>
    <string name="dc8" translatable="false">هَدُ أَنْ لا إِلَـهَ إِلاّ اللهُ وَحْدَهُ لا شَريـكَ لَـهُ وَأَشْهَدُ أَنَّ مُحَمّـداً عَبْـدُهُ وَرَسـولُـه</string>
    <string name="tc8">I bear witness that none has the right to be worshipped except Allah,
        alone without partner, and I bear witness that Muhammad is His slave and Messenger.</string>
    <string name="dc9" translatable="false">ِسْمِ اللهِ ، تَوَكَّلْـتُ عَلى اللهِ وَلا حَوْلَ وَلا قُـوَّةَ إِلاّ بِالله</string>
    <string name="tc9">In the name of Allah, I place my trust in Allah, and there is no might
        nor power except with Allah.</string>
    <string name="dc10" translatable="false">بِسْـمِ اللهِ وَلَجْنـا، وَبِسْـمِ اللهِ خَـرَجْنـا، وَعَلـى رَبِّنـا تَوَكّلْـنا</string>
    <string name="tc10">In the name of Allah we enter and in the name of Allah we leave, and upon our Lord
        we place our trust.</string>
    <string name="dc11" translatable="false">عوذُ باللهِ العَظيـم وَبِوَجْهِـهِ الكَرِيـم وَسُلْطـانِه
        القَديـم مِنَ الشّيْـطانِ الرَّجـيم،[ بِسْـمِ الله، وَالصَّلاةُ]
        [وَالسَّلامُ عَلى رَسولِ الله]، اللّهُـمَّ افْتَـحْ لي أَبْوابَ رَحْمَتـِك</string>
    <string name="tc11">I take refuge with Allah, The Supreme and with His Noble Face,
        and His eternal authority from the accursed devil. In the name of Allah,
        and prayers and peace be upon the Messenger of Allah. O Allah, open the gates of Your mercy for me.</string>
    <string name="dc12" translatable="false">عوذُ باللهِ العَظيـم وَبِوَجْهِـهِ الكَرِيـم وَسُلْطـانِه القَديـم مِنَ الشّيْـطانِ الرَّجـيم،[ بِسْـمِ الله، وَالصَّلاةُ] [وَالسَّلامُ عَلى رَسولِ الله]،
        اللّهُـمَّ افْتَـحْ لي أَبْوابَ رَحْمَتـِك</string>
    <string name="tc12">I take refuge with Allah, The Supreme and with His Noble Face,
        and His eternal authority from the accursed devil. In the name of Allah,
        and prayers and peace be upon the Messenger of Allah. O Allah, open the gates of Your mercy for me.</string>
    <string name="dc13" translatable="false">بِسمِ الله وَالصّلاةُ وَالسّلامُ عَلى رَسولِ الله، اللّهُـمَّ إِنّـي أَسْأَلُكَ مِـنْ فَضْـلِك،
        اللّهُـمَّ اعصِمْنـي مِنَ الشَّيْـطانِ الرَّجـيم</string>
    <string name="tc13">In the name of Allah, and prayers and peace be upon the Messenger of Allah.
        O Allah, I ask You from Your favour. O Allah, guard me from the accursed devil.</string>
    <string name="dc14" translatable="false">اللّهُـمَّ رَبَّ هَذِهِ الدّعْـوَةِ التّـامَّة وَالصّلاةِ القَـائِمَة
        آتِ محَـمَّداً الوَسيـلةَ وَالْفَضـيلَة وَابْعَـثْه
        مَقـامـاً مَحـموداً الَّذي وَعَـدْتَه إِنَّـكَ
        لا تُـخْلِفُ الميـعاد</string>
    <string name="tc14">O Allah, Owner of this perfect call and Owner of this prayer to be performed,
        bestow upon Muhammad al-waseelah and al-fadeelah and send him upon a praised platform which
        You have promised him. Verily, You never fail in Your promise.’ al-waseelah: A station in
        paradise. al-fadeelah: A rank above the rest of creation. praised platform: One in which all
        of creation will praise him on, in order to bring about the account quickly and be relieved
        from the lengthy standing or the role of intercession.</string>
    <string name="dc15" translatable="false">اللّهُـمَّ باعِـدْ بَيـني وَبَيْنَ خَطـايايَ كَما باعَدْتَ بَيْنَ
        المَشْرِقِ وَالمَغْرِبْ ، اللّهُـمَّ نَقِّنـي مِنْ خَطايايَ كَمـا يُـنَقَّى الثَّـوْبُ الأَبْيَضُ
        مِنَ الدَّنَسْ ، اللّهُـمَّ اغْسِلْنـي مِنْ خَطايـايَ بِالثَّلـجِ وَالمـاءِ وَالْبَرَد</string>
    <string name="tc15">How perfect You are O Allah, and I praise You. Blessed be Your name,
        and lofty is Your position and none has the right to be worshipped except You.</string>
    <string name="dc16" translatable="false">سُبْـحانَ رَبِّـيَ الْعَظـيم . (ثلاثاً)</string>
    <string name="tc16">How perfect my Lord is, The Supreme. (three times)</string>
    <string name="dc17" translatable="false">سَمِـعَ اللهُ لِمَـنْ حَمِـدَه</string>
    <string name="tc17">May Allah answer he who praises Him.’ This supplication is to be made while rising.</string>
    <string name="dc18" translatable="false">سُبْـحانَ رَبِّـيَ الأَعْلـى . (ثلاثاً )</string>
    <string name="tc18">How perfect my Lord is, The Most High. (three times)</string>
    <string name="dc19" translatable="false">رَبِّ اغْفِـرْ لي ، رَبِّ اغْفِـرْ لي</string>
    <string name="tc19">My Lord forgive me, My Lord forgive me.</string>
    <string name="dc20" translatable="false">سَجَدَ وَجْهِيَ لِلَّذِي خَلَقَهُ،
        وَشَقَّ سَمْعَهُ وَبَصَرَهُ، بِحَوْلِهِ وَقُوَّتِهِ، فَتَبَارَكَ اللهُ أَحسَنُ الْخَالِقِي</string>
    <string name="tc20">My face fell prostrate before He who created it and brought forth its faculties of
        hearing and seeing by His might and power. So Blessed is Allah, the best of creators.</string>
    <string name="dc21" translatable="false">التَّحِيّـاتُ للهِ وَالصَّلَـواتُ والطَّيِّـبات ، السَّلامُ عَلَيـكَ أَيُّهـا النَّبِـيُّ
        وَرَحْمَـةُ اللهِ وَبَرَكـاتُه ، السَّلامُ عَلَيْـنا وَعَلـى عِبـادِ كَ الصَّـالِحـين
        . أَشْـهَدُ أَنْ لا إِلـهَ إِلاّ الله ، وَأَشْـهَدُ أَنَّ مُحَمّـداً عَبْـدُهُ وَرَسـولُه</string>
    <string name="tc21">At-tahiyyat is for Allah. All acts of worship and good deeds are for Him. Peace
        and the mercy and blessings of Allah be upon you O Prophet. Peace be upon us and all of Allah\'s
        righteous servants. I bear witness that none has the right to be worshipped except Allah and I
        bear witness that Muhammad is His slave and Messenger.’ At-tahiyyat: all words which indicate
        the glorification of Allah. His eternal existence, His perfection and His sovereignty.</string>
    <string name="dc22" translatable="false">اللّهُـمَّ صَلِّ عَلـى مُحمَّـد،
        وَعَلـى آلِ مُحمَّد، كَمـا صَلَّيـتَ عَلـىإبْراهـيمَ وَعَلـى آلِ إبْراهـيم،
        إِنَّكَ حَمـيدٌ مَجـيد ، اللّهُـمَّ بارِكْ عَلـى مُحمَّـد، وَعَلـى آلِ مُحمَّـد،
        كَمـا بارِكْتَ عَلـىإبْراهـيمَ وَعَلـى آلِ إبْراهيم، إِنَّكَ حَمـيدٌ مَجـيد
</string>
    <string name="tc22">O Allah, send prayers upon Muhammad and the followers of Muhammad,
        just as You sent prayers upon Ibraheem and upon the followers of Ibraheem. Verily,
        You are full of praise and majesty. O Allah, send blessings upon Mohammad and upon
        the family of Muhammad, just as You sent blessings upon Ibraheem and upon the family
        of Ibraheem. Verily, You are full of praise and majesty.’ send prayers: praise and exalt
        him in the highest and superior of gatherings: that of the closest angels to Allah. (al)
        has been translated in it’s broadest sense: some scholars are of the view that the meaning
        here is more specific and that it means: his (saw) followers from among his family.
</string>
    <string name="dc23" translatable="false">اللّهُـمَّ إِنِّـي أَعـوذُ بِكَ مِـنْ عَذابِ القَـبْر، وَمِـنْ عَذابِ جَهَـنَّم،
        وَمِـنْ فِتْـنَةِ المَحْـيا وَالمَمـات، وَمِـنْ شَـرِّ فِتْـنَةِ المَسيحِ الدَّجّال</string>
    <string name="tc23">O Allah, I take refuge in You from the punishment of the grave, from the torment of
        the Fire, from the trials and tribulations of life and death and from the evil affliction
        of Al-Maseeh Ad-Dajjal.</string>
    <string name="dc24" translatable="false">أَسْـتَغْفِرُ الله . (ثَلاثاً) اللّهُـمَّ أَنْـتَ السَّلامُ
        ، وَمِـنْكَ السَّلام ، تَبارَكْتَ يا ذا الجَـلالِ وَالإِكْـرام</string>
    <string name="tc24">I ask Allah for forgiveness. (three times) O Allah, You are As-Salam and from
        You is all peace, blessed are You, O Possessor of majesty and honour. AS-Salam: The One Who is
        free from all defects and deficiencies.</string>
    <string name="dc25" translatable="false">اللّهُـمَّ إِنِّـي أَسْتَخيـرُكَ بِعِاْـمِك،
        وَأسْتَقْـدِرُكَ بِقُـدْرَتِـك، وَأَسْـألُـكَ مِنْ فَضْـلِكَ العَظـيم، فَإِنَّـكَ
        تَقْـدِرُ وَلا أَقْـدِر، وَتَـعْلَـمُ وَلا أَعْلَـم، وَأَنْـتَ عَلاّمُ الغُـيوب،
        اللّهُـمَّ إِنْ كُنْـتَ تَعْـلَمُ أَنَّ هـذا الأمْـرَ- وَيُسَـمِّي حاجَتَـه
        - خَـيْرٌ لي في دينـي وَمَعـاشي وَعاقِـبَةِ أَمْـري، فَاقْـدُرْهُ
        لي وَيَسِّـرْهُ لي ثـمَّ بارِكْ لي فيـه، وَإِنْ كُنْـتَ تَعْـلَمُ أَنَّ هـذا
        الأمْـرَ شَـرٌ لي في دينـي وَمَعـاشي وَعاقِـبَةِ أَمْـري، فَاصْرِفْـهُ
        وَاصْرِفْني عَنْـهُ وَاقْـدُرْ لي الخَـيْرَ حَيْـثُ كانَ ثُـمَّ أَرْضِـني بِـه</string>
    <string name="tc25">On the authority of Jabir Ibn Abdullah (ra) he said: The Prophet would
        instruct us to pray for guidance in all of our concerns, just as he would teach us a chapter
        from the Quran. He (saw) would say If any of you intends to undertake a matter then let him
        pray two supererogatory units (two rakah nafilah) of prayer and after which he should supplicate</string>
    <string name="dc26" translatable="false">أَمْسَيْـنا وَأَمْسـى المـلكُ لله وَالحَمدُ لله ،
        لا إلهَ إلاّ اللّهُ وَحدَهُ لا شَريكَ لهُ، لهُ المُـلكُ ولهُ الحَمْـد، وهُوَ
        على كلّ شَيءٍ قدير ، رَبِّ أسْـأَلُـكَ خَـيرَ ما في هـذهِ اللَّـيْلَةِ
        وَخَـيرَ ما بَعْـدَهـا ، وَأَعـوذُ بِكَ مِنْ شَـرِّ هـذهِ اللَّـيْلةِ وَشَر
        ِّ ما بَعْـدَهـا ، رَبِّ أَعـوذُبِكَ مِنَ الْكَسَـلِ وَسـوءِ الْكِـبَر ،
        رَبِّ أَعـوذُبِكَ مِنْ عَـذابٍ في النّـارِ وَعَـذابٍ في القَـبْر .</string>
    <string name="tc26">In morning</string>
    <string name="dc27" translatable="false">{اللّهُ لاَ إِلَـهَ إِلاَّ هُوَ الْحَيُّ الْقَيُّومُ لاَ تَأْخُذُهُ سِنَةٌ وَلاَ نَوْمٌ لَّهُ مَا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ
        وَمَا فِي الأَرْضِ مَن ذَا الَّذِي يَشْفَعُ عِنْدَهُ إِلاَّ بِإِذْنِهِ يَعْلَمُ مَا بَيْنَ أ
        َيْدِيهِمْ وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ وَلاَ يُحِيطُونَ بِشَيْءٍ مِّنْ عِلْمِهِ إِلاَّ بِمَا شَاء وَسِعَ
        كُرْسِيُّهُ السَّمَوَاتِ وَالأَرْضَ وَلاَ يَؤُودُهُ حِفْظُهُمَا وَهُوَ الْعَلِيُّ الْعَظِيمُ }</string>
    <string name="tc27">The Prophet (S) also said: ‘When you are about to sleep recite ayat-al-kursee
        (The verse of the foot-stool, chapter 2:255) till the end of the verse for there will
        remain over you a protection from Allah and no devil will draw near to you until morning.’</string>
    <string name="dc28" translatable="false">لا إِلَهَ~َ إِلاَّ اللَّهُ الوَاحِدُ القَهَّارُ،
        رَبُّ السَّمَوَاتِ وَالأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا، العَزِيْزُ الغَفَّارُ</string>
    <string name="tc28">Aisha narrated that the Messenger of Allah (saw) used to say at night if he
        turned during sleep:None has the right to be worshipped except Allah, The One, AL-Qahhar.
        Lord of the heavens and the Earth and all between them, The Exalted in Might,
        The Oft-Forgiving.AL-Qahhar:The One Who has subdued all of creation and
        Whom all of creation are subservient to. All movements occur by His will.</string>
    <string name="dc29" translatable="false">أَعُوْذُ بِكَلِمَاتِ اللَّهِ التَّامَّاتِ مِنْ غَضَبِه
        ِِ وَعِقَابِهِ، وَشَرِّ عِبَادِه ِِ وَمِنْ هَمَزَاتِ الشَّيْاطِيْنِ وَأَنْ يَحْضُرُوْنَ.</string>
    <string name="tc29">‘I take refuge in the perfect words of Allah from His anger and punishment,
        and from the evil of His servants, and from the madness and appearance of devils.’</string>
    <string name="dc30" translatable="false">ينفث عن يساره (ثلاثا) يستعيذ بالله من
        الشيطان ومن شر ما رأى (ثلاث مرات) لا يحدث بها أحدا.
        يتحول عن جنبه الذي كان عليه. يَنْفُثُ عَنْ يَسَارِهِ (ثَلاثاً)
        يَسْتَعِيْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَ الشَّيْطَانِ وَمِنْ شَرِّ مَا رَأَى (ثَلاثَ مَرَّاتٍ)
        لا يُحَدِّثُ بِهَا أَحَداً. يَتَحَوَّلُ عَنْ جَنْبِهِ الَّذِي كَانَ عَلَيْهِ.</string>
    <string name="tc30">‘The righteous dream is from Allah and the bad dream is from the devil,
        so if anyone sees something which pleases him then he should only relate it to one whom he loves…\'</string>
    <string name="dc31" translatable="false">اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّي أَعُوْذُ بِرِضَاكَ مِنْ سَخَطِكَ، وَبِمُعَافَاتِكَ مِنْ عُقُوْبَتِكَ، وَأَعُوْذُ بِكَ مِنْكَ،
        لا أُحْصِي ثَنَاءً عَلَيْكَ، أَنْتَ كَمَا أَثْنَيْتَ عَلَى نَفْسِكَ</string>
    <string name="tc31">‘O Allah, I take refuge within Your pleasure from Your displeasure and
        within Your pardon from Your punishment, and I take refuge in You from You.
        I cannot enumerate Your praise. You are as You have praised Yourself.’</string>
    <string name="dc32" translatable="false">سَبِّحِ اِسْمَ رَبِّكَ الأَعْلَى (قُلْ يَا أَيُّهَا الكَافِرُوْنَ…) (قُلْ هُوَ الله
        ُ أَحَدٌ…) سبْحَانَ المَلِكِ القُدُّوْسِ (ثَلاثَ مَرَّات) وَالثَّالِثَةُ
        يَجْهَرُ بِهَا وَيَمُدُّ بِهَا صَوْتَهُ، [ رَبِّ المَلائِكَةِ وَالرُّوْحِ]</string>
    <string name="tc32">The Messenger of Allah (S) would recite (the following chapters)
        during the witr prayer suras:[Al-Ala], [Al-kafiroon], [Al-ikhlas]after giving salam
        he would supplicate three times: ‘How perfect The King, The Holy One is.’ (three times)
        ..on the third time he would raise his voice, elongate it and add: ‘Lord of the angles
        and the Rooh (i.e. Jibraeel).</string>
    <string name="dc33" translatable="false">اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّي أَعُوْذُ بِكَ مِنَ الهَمِّ وَالحُزْنِ،
        وَالعَجْزِ وَالكَسَلِ وَالبُخْلِ وَالجُبْنِ، وَضَلْعِ الدَّيْنِ وَغَلَبَةِ الرِّجَالِ</string>
    <string name="tc33">‘O Allah, I take refuge in You from anxiety and sorrow, weakness and
        laziness, miserliness and cowardice, the burden of debts and from being over powered by men.’</string>
    <string name="dc34" translatable="false">لا إِلَهََ إِلاَّ اللهُ العَظِيْمُ الحَلِيْمُ، لا إِلَهََ إِلاَّ اللهُ رَبُّ العَرْشِ العَظِيْمِ، لا إِلَهَ~َ
        إِلاَّ اللهُ رَبُّ السَّمَوَاتِ وَرَبُّ الأَرْضِ وَرَبُّ العَرْشِ الكَرِيْمِ</string>
    <string name="tc34">‘None has the right to be worshipped except Allah Forbearing. None has the
        right to be worshipped except Allah, Lord of the magnificent throne. None has the right to
        be worshipped except Allah, Lord of the heavens, Lord of the Earth and Lord of the noble throne.’</string>
    <string name="dc35" translatable="false">اللَّهُمَّ إِنَّا نَجْعَلُكَ فِي نُحَورِهِمْ، وَنَعُوْذُ بِكَ مِنْ شُرُوْرِهِمْ</string>
    <string name="tc35">‘O Allah, we place You before them and we take refuge in You from their evil.’</string>
    <string name="dc36" translatable="false">يَقُوْلُ: آمَنْتُ بِاللهِ وَرُسُلِهِ</string>
    <string name="tc36">One should say: ‘I have believed in Allah and His Messenger.’</string>
    <string name="dc37" translatable="false">اللَّهمَّ اكْفِنِي بِحَلالِكَ عَنْ حَرَامِكَ، وَأَغْنِنِي بِفَضْلِكَ عَمَّنْ سِوَاكَ</string>
    <string name="tc37">‘O Allah, make what is lawful enough for me, as opposed to what is unlawful,
        and spare me by Your grace, of need of others.’</string>
    <string name="dc38" translatable="false">أعوذ بالله من الشيطان الرجيم واتفل على يسارك ( ثلاثا )</string>
    <string name="tc38">Uthman Ibn Al-Aas narrated: I said ‘O Messenger of Allah (saw), verily the
        devil comes between me and my prayer and recitation making me confused’ The Messenger of
        Allah (saw) replied ‘That is a devil called Khanzab, so if you sense his presence then seek
        refuge in Allah from him and spit (A form of spitting comprising mainly of air with little
        spittle) on your left side three times.’</string>
    <string name="dc39" translatable="false">اللَّهمَّ لا سَهْلَ إِلاَّ مَا جَعَلتَه ُُ سَهْلا، ً وَأَنْتَ تَجْعَلُ الحَزَنَ إِذَا شِئْتَ سَهْلا</string>
    <string name="tc39">‘O Allah, there is no ease except in that which You have made easy,
        and You make the difficulty, if You wish, easy.’</string>
    <string name="dc40" translatable="false">ما من عبد يذنب ذنبا فيحسن الطهور،
        ثم يقوم فيصلي ركعتين، ثم يستغفر الله إلا غفر الله له</string>
    <string name="tc40">‘Any servant who commits a sin and as a result, performs ablution, prays
        two units of prayer (i.e. two rakahs) and then seeks Allah’s forgiveness, Allah would
        forgive him.’</string>
    <string name="dc41" translatable="false">الإستعاذة بالله منه</string>
    <string name="tc41">Seeking refuge from him.</string>
    <string name="dc42" translatable="false">حَسْبِيَ اللَّهُ وَنِعْمَ الوَكِيْلُ</string>
    <string name="tc42">‘Allah is sufficient for me, and how fine a trustee (He is).’</string>
    <string name="dc43" translatable="false">كان رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم يعوذ الحسن والحسين:أُعِيْذُكُمَا
        بِكَلِمَاتِ اللَّهِ التَّامَّةِ، مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَان ٍ وَهَامَّة، ٍ وَمِنْ كُلِّ عَيْن ٍ لامَّة</string>
    <string name="tc43">Ibn Abbas related that the Messenger of Allah (saw) used to commend Al-Hasan
        and Al-Husayn to Allah’s protection, saying:‘I commend you two to the protection of Allah’s
        perfect words from every devil, vermin, and every evil eye.’</string>
    <string name="dc44" translatable="false">لا بَأْسَ طَهُوْر ٌ إِنْ شَاءَ ال</string>
    <string name="tc44">When the Prophet (saw) would enter upon a sick person, he would say:
        ‘Never mind, may it (the sickness) be a purification, if Allah wills.’</string>
    <string name="dc45" translatable="false">قَالَ صَلَّى اللهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَّمَ: \" إِذَا عَادَ الرَّجُلُ أَخَاهُ المُسْلِمَ مَشَى
        فِي خِرَافَةِ الجَنَّةِ حَتَّى يَجْلِسَ فَإِذَا جَلَسَ غَمَرَتْهُ الرَّحْمَةُ،
        فَإِنْ كَانَ غُدْوَةً صَلَّى عَلَيْهِ سَبْعُوْنَ أَلْفَ مَلَكٍ حَتَّى يُمْسِيَ،
        وَإِنْ كَانَ مَسَاءً صَلَّى عَلَيْهِ سَبْعُوْنَ أَلْفَ مَلَكٍ حَتَّى يُصْبِحَ</string>
    <string name="tc45">‘Ali Ibn Abi Talib (ra) related that he heard the Messenger of Allah
        (saw) say:‘If a man calls on his sick Muslim brother, it is as if he walks reaping the
        fruits of Paradise until he sits, and when he sits he is showered in mercy, and if this
        was in the morning, seventy thousand angles send prayers upon him until the evening, and
        if this was in the evening, seventy thousand angles send prayers upon him until the morning.’</string>
    <string name="dc46" translatable="false">اللَّهمَّ اغْفِرْ لِي وَارْحَمْنِي وَأَلْحِقْنِي بِالرَّفِيْقِ الأَعْلَى</string>
    <string name="tc46">‘O Allah, forgive me, have mercy upon me and unite me with the higher
        companions.Refer to the Quran, chapter 4, verse: 69</string>
    <string name="dc47" translatable="false">لا إِلَهََ إِلاَّ ال</string>
    <string name="tc47">Those around the sick should instruct and encourage him to say the shahadah.
        ‘He whose last words are:‘None has the right to be worshipped except Allah. will enter Paradise.’</string>
    <string name="dc48" translatable="false">إِنَّا للهِ وَإِنَّا إِلَيْهِ رَاجِعُوْنَ،
        اللَّهمَّ أْجُرْنِي فِي مُصِيْبَتِي، وَاخْلُفْ لِي خَيْرا ً مِنْهَا</string>
    <string name="tc48">‘To Allah we belong and unto Him is our return.O Allah,
        recompense me for my affliction and replace it for me with something better.’</string>
    <string name="dc49" translatable="false">اللَّهمَّ اغْفِرْ لِ-فُلان ٍ بِاسْمِهِ- وَارْفَعْ دَرَجَتَه ُُ فِي المَهْدِيِّيْنَ،
        وَاخْلُفْهُ فِي عَقِبِه ِِ فِي الغَابِرِيْنَ،
        وَاغْفِرْ لَنَا وَلَه ُُ يَا رَبَّ العَالَمِيْنَ،
        وَافْسَحْ لَه ُُ فِي قَبْرِه ِِ وَنَوِّرْ لَه ُُ فِيْهِ</string>
    <string name="tc49">‘O Allah, forgive (mention the name of the deceased here)
        and raise his rank among the rightly guided, and be a successor to whom he
        has left behind, and forgive us and him O Lord of the worlds. Make spacious
        his grave and illuminate it for him.’</string>
    <string name="dc50" translatable="false">اللَّهمَّ اغْفِرْ لَه ُُ وَارْحَمْهُ، وَعَافِه ِِ وَاعْفُ عَنْهُ، وَأَكْرِمْ نُزُلَهُ،
        وَوَسِّعْ مُدْخَلَهُ، وَاغْسِلْهُ بِالمَاءِ وَالثَّلْجِ وَالبَرَدِ،
        وَنَقِّه ِِ مِنَ الخَطَايَا كَمَا نَقَّيْتَ الثَّوْبَ الأَبْيَضَ مِنَ
        الدَّنَسِ، وَأَبْدِلْهُ دَاراً خَيْرا ً مِنْ دَارِهِ، وَأَهْلاً خَيْرا
        ً مِنْ أَهْلِهِ، وَزَوْجَاً خَيْرا ً مِنْ زَوْجِهِ، وَأَدْخِلْهُ الجَنَّةَ،
        وَأَعِذْهُ مِنْ عَذَابِ القَبْرِ وَعَذَابِ النَّار</string>
    <string name="tc50">‘O Allah, forgive and have mercy upon him, excuse him and pardon him,
        and make honourable his reception. Expand his entry, and cleanse him with water, snow,
        and ice, and purify him of sin as a white robe is purified of filth. Exchange his home
        for a better home, and his family for a better family, and his spouse for a better spouse.
        Admit him into the Garden, protect him from the punishment of the grave and the torment of the Fire.’</string>
    <string name="ablution_explain">This is based on the following: Says Allah, If you are sexually impure,
        cleanse yourselves, that is, perform ghusl, and They ask you concerning menstruation.
        Say: \'It is an illness, so leave women alone at such times and go not in unto them
        until they are cleansed, that is, until they perform ghusl. The proof that cleansing
        means ghusl is in the verse, O you who believe, draw not unto the prayer when you are
        drunk until you know what you utter, nor when you are polluted, save when journeying
        upon the road, until you have bathed (taghtasilu). This shows that ghusl, the washing
        of all bodily parts, is meant.</string>
    <string name="ghusl1">According to the practice of the Prophet, upon whom be peace, the
        correct manner of performing ghusl is:</string>
    <string name="gusl2">01. Wash both hands three times.</string>
    <string name="ghus3">02. Wash the private parts.</string>
    <string name="ghus4">03. Make a complete ablution (like the one made for prayer—the
        Prophet used to delay washing his feet until the end of his ghusl if he was using a
        tub, and so on),</string>
    <string name="ghus05">04. Rub water through one\'s hair three times, letting the water
        reach down to the roots of the hair,</string>
    <string name="ghus7">05. Pour water over the entire body, beginning with the right side,
        then the left, washing under the armpits, inside the ears, inside the navel, inside
        the toes and whatever part of the body can be easily rubbed.</string>
    <string name="ghus8">This account is based on the following report from
        \'Aishah: When the Prophet, upon whom be peace, took his bath after
        sexual intercourse, he would begin by washing his hands. Then he would pour
        water from his right hand to his left and wash his sexual organs, make the ablution
        for prayer, take some water and put his fingers to the roots of his hair to the extent
        that he sees that the skin is wet, then pour water over his head three times and then
        over the rest of his body.</string>
    <string name="ghus9">In one narration it states, He used to rub his head with his hands
        until he was certain the water reached his skin, and then he poured water over it three times.
        It is also related that she said, When the Prophet would perform ghusl after having had sexual
        intercourse, he would call for some water, which he would pour on his right hand to wash the
        right side of his head and then the left.</string>
    <string name="ghus10">He would then take water with both hands and pour it over his head.
        Said Maimunah, I put water out for the Messenger of Allah to perform ghusl.
        He washed his hands two or three times, and then he poured water from his
        right hand to his left and washed his private parts, wiped his hands on the
        earth, rinsed his mouth and nose, washed his face and hands, washed his head
        three times, poured water over his body, and finally moved from his place and washed
        his feet. I brought him a towel, but he did not take it, for he shook the water off
        with his hands.</string>
    <string name="wudu">Since Islam teaches us that intention forms the basis of any action,
        it is necessary that, before you perform Wudu, you make the niyyat or intention for it.
        This will not be a verbal act - you only have to mentally prepare yourself for an act that
        will cleanse and purify you.</string>
    <string name="wudu1">Recite bismi-llāhi ar-raḥmāni ar-raḥīmi (In the name of Allah, the most Gracious,
        the most Merciful).</string>
    <string name="wudu2">Completely wash your right hand three times with clean water,
        then move on to the left and repeat. When washing, remember not to miss any part of the hands -
        wash between the fingers and thumb, too.</string>
    <string name="wudu3">Take water in your right palm and rinse your mouth with it, thrice.
        Do not swallow the water on purpose, but spit it out every time.</string>
    <string name="wudu4">Using your right hand, carefully and gently put water into your nostrils,
        before exhaling it. Perform this step three times.</string>
    <string name="wudu5">Thoroughly wash your face, beginning from the hairline on your forehead
        and from one ear to the other. This step, too, must be performed three times.</string>
    <string name="wudu6">Begin with your right hand. Wet it with water, and wash from your wrist
        up to your elbow. Repeat thrice; then do the same to your left arm.</string>
    <string name="wudu7">Usually, Masah refers to the religious act of cleaning one\'s head, in a
        specific way, with a small amount of water. For performing Masah, wet your hands and place
        your palms, flat, on the top of your head (where the hairline begins). Wipe them to the back
        of your neck, and then back again to the front. Now wet the back of both ears
        by placing your thumbs behind them. Use your index and middle fingers to wash
        the front and back of your ears. Masah is done only once.</string>
    <string name="wudu8">Start with your right foot. Wash it thrice from the toes,
        up to the ankles. Make sure you wash between your toes, too. Do the same to your left foot.
        Remember: Once Wudu is performed, it does not need to (but can) be performed
        again until it is invalidated.</string>
    <string name="bannerid" translatable="false" >ca-app-pub-2868811788162661/8748513167</string>
    <string name="quooadtext" translatable="false" >If the required number of Rakats is two the salat would proceed to next recitaion.</string>
    <string name="quood" translatable="false">Quood</string>
    <string name="play_tashhad" translatable="false">Play Tashhad</string>
    <string name="durood_ibraheem" translatable="false">Durood Ibraheem</string>
    <string name="play_dua" translatable="false">Play Dua</string>
    <string name="salam" translatable="false">Salam</string>
    <string name="salam_play" translatable="false">salam play</string>


    <string-array name="language_array">
        <item>Select Language</item>
        <item>Hindi</item>
        <item>Sindhi</item>
        <item>Urdu</item>
        <item>English</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
